- Are you ready, kids?
- 孩子们，你们准备好了吗？
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- I can't hear you.
- 我听不到你说话。
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- ♪ Ohh... ♪
- ♪ 哦...♪
♪ Who lives in a pineapple
under the sea? ♪
♪ 谁住在菠萝里
在海底？ ♪
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ Absorbent and yellow
and porous is he ♪
- ♪ 吸水性和黄色
他是多孔的 ♪
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ If nautical nonsense
be something you wish ♪
- ♪ 如果航海废话
成为你想要的东西♪
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ Then drop on the deck
and flop like a fish ♪
- ♪ 然后落在甲板上
然后像鱼一样扑通扑通♪
all: SpongeBob SquarePants!
- Ready?
所有：海绵宝宝！
- 准备好？
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
SpongeBob SquarePants!
- SpongeBob
- 海绵宝宝
SquarePants!
方裤！
[laughing]
[笑]
♪ ♪
[peaceful music]
[平静的音乐]
♪ ♪
- ♪ La-la-la-la-la-
la-la-la-la ♪
- ♪ 啦啦啦啦啦-
啦啦啦啦♪
♪ La-la-la-la-la-la ♪
♪ 啦啦啦啦啦啦 ♪
♪ La-la-la-la-la-la-la ♪
♪ 啦啦啦啦啦啦啦啦 ♪
♪ La-la-la-la-la ♪
♪ 啦啦啦啦啦 ♪
♪ La-la-la-la--♪
♪ 啦啦啦啦——♪
all: Ahh!
全体：啊！
- ♪ La-la-la-la-la-la-la ♪
- ♪ 啦啦啦啦啦啦啦啦 ♪
♪ La-la, la-la-la-la-la-la-la,
la-la-la-la-la ♪
♪ 啦啦啦啦啦啦啦啦啦，
啦啦啦啦啦♪
♪ La-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la ♪
♪ 啦啦啦啦啦啦啦啦啦啦 ♪
- You know that child
we were planning on having?
- 你认识那个孩子
我们计划有什么？
both: Let's forget it.
两人：算了吧。
- ♪ La-la-la-la-la-la-la,
la-la-la-laaa ♪
- ♪ 啦啦啦啦啦啦啦啦，
啦啦啦啦啦♪
- Ah! SpongeBob, I could hear
you caterwauling a mile away.
- 啊！海绵宝宝，我听见了
你在一英里外嚎叫。
- Aw, thanks,
and thanks for watching
- 噢，谢谢，
感谢您的观看
my Sea Chimps
while I'm at work.
我的海黑猩猩
当我在工作的时候。
- They're already
in an aquarium.
- 他们已经
在水族馆里。
Why don't you just
leave 'em at home?
你为什么不直接
把他们留在家里？
- Hm.
- 嗯。
I think Gary might be
trying to eat them.
我认为加里可能是
试图吃掉它们。
I found saliva on the glass.
我在玻璃上发现了口水。
- So what do I need
to do for them?
- 那么我需要什么
为他们做什么？
- Nothing! They'll
take care of themselves.
- 没有什么！他们会
照顾好自己。
Oh? Hm!
Well, I got to go.
哦？嗯！
好吧，我得走了。
Here's my breeze.
Whoa-ow-ow-ow!
这是我的微风。
哇哦哦！
- When will you ever learn
that a tiny pipsqueak like you
- 你什么时候才能学会
像你这样的小家伙
will never, ever,
take over anything.
永远、永远、
接管任何事情。
What do you call this
gizmo you made anyway?
你管这个叫什么
你还是做了小发明吗？
[mechanical rattling]
[机械嘎嘎声]
- [coughing]
- [咳嗽]
The Takeover-er-er.
接管-呃-呃。
- [laughing]
That's just stupid.
- [笑]
那太愚蠢了。
[whooshing]
[呼啸]
- Morning.
- Morning...
- 早晨。
- 早晨...
- And don't forget
your Rube Goldfish device!
- 别忘了
你的鲁布金鱼设备！
[whirling]
There we go.
[旋转]
我们开始吧。
- Ah!
- 啊！
Ahhh!
啊啊！
[crashing]
[崩溃]
[pained grunting]
[痛苦的咕哝]
[sighing]
[叹气]
[cracking]
[开裂]
Honey, I'm home.
亲爱的，我回来了。
What's this stupid thing?
这是什么蠢事？
- Those are
SpongeBob's Sea Chimps.
- 那些是
海绵宝宝的海黑猩猩。
You don't need
to bother with them.
你不需要
去打扰他们。
I'm going back
to my shows now.
我要回去了
现在开始我的表演。
- Uh!
- Oh!
- 呃！
- 哦！
- Uh!
- Ah!
- 呃！
- 啊！
- Oh! Ah.
- 哦！啊。
- Hmm. Huh?
- 唔。啊？
Sea Chimps, huh?
海黑猩猩，是吗？
all: ♪ La-la-la-la-
la-la-la-la-la-la ♪
全体：♪ 啦啦啦啦-
啦啦啦啦啦啦♪
♪ La-la-la-la-la-la-la,
la-la-la-la-la ♪
♪ 啦啦啦啦啦啦啦啦，
啦啦啦啦啦♪
- Wait a minute.
- 等一下。
Maybe I've been
going about this
也许我曾经
正在做这件事
world conquest thing
all wrong.
征服世界的事
都错了。
Maybe I should start small
and work my way up!
也许我应该从小事做起
并努力向上！
[maniacal laughter]
[疯狂的笑声]
This shrink belt will allow me
这条收缩带可以让我
to walk among
those little monkeys.
行走其中
那些小猴子。
Alley-oop!
空中接力！
[laughing]
[笑]
Ah!
啊!
[whimpering]
[呜咽]
Too small, too small!
太小了，太小了！
Huh? [mumbling]
啊？ [咕哝]
Hey, why are you idiots
so short?
嘿，你们为什么是白痴
这么短？
You afraid of me?
你怕我吗？
You gonna cry?
你会哭吗？
- [sobbing]
- [抽泣]
[all screaming]
[所有人尖叫]
Listen here,
you pint sized twerps.
听这里，
你们这些小傻瓜。
I'm taking over
your monkey town, see?
我来接手
你的猴城，看到了吗？
[nervous murmuring]
[紧张的低语]
Do you little cretins have
a king or a queen or something?
你们这些小白痴有吗
国王或王后什么的？
- Um, I am the king.
- 嗯，我是国王。
- Yeah? Well now I'm the king!
- 是的？好吧，现在我是国王了！
- Wow, thank you, sir!
I mean, sire.
- 哇，谢谢你，先生！
我是说，陛下。
I'm not the king!
我不是国王！
I'm not the king-ing-ing!
我不是王者！
- Why was that so easy?
- 为什么这么容易？
It's so easy
because I'm so big and smart!
就是这么简单
因为我又大又聪明！
That's why!
这就是为什么！
Ah!
啊!
Well,
what are you all waiting for?
嗯，
你们还在等什么？
Follow your leader!
Fall!
跟随你的领导！
落下！
[all whimper]
[全都呜咽]
[trumpeting]
[喇叭声]
That's right,
bring me all your valuables.
没错，
把你所有的贵重物品都给我带来。
What are those?
Dentures? Hand them over.
那些是什么？
假牙？把它们交给我。
That's more like it.
这更像是这样。
I want to be the only one
in town with stuff!
我想成为唯一的一个
在城里带着东西！
Ah!
啊!
all: Ah!
众人：啊！
- I'm tired of walking.
Carry me!
- 我走累了。
带我吧！
- Ah!
- Father!
- 啊！
- 父亲！
- [laughing] Right in the head!
You guys are idiots.
- [笑]就在脑子里！
你们都是白痴。
I'm the smart one.
I've got the best ideas.
我是最聪明的那个
我有最好的主意。
Hey, you!
Here's a grape-flavored idea!
嘿，你！
这是一个葡萄味的主意！
Hi-yah!
嗨呀！
- Oh!
- Ah!
- 哦！
- 啊！
- [whimpering]
Ah!
- [呜咽]
啊！
- Okay, that's enough.
I'm bored.
- 好吧，够了。
我很无聊。
[engine revving]
[发动机转速]
Yeah!
是的！
I rule you,
I rule you, I rule you.
我统治你，
我统治你，我统治你。
I rule you, you, you,
and you--Ah!
我统治你，你，你，
而你——啊！
Ahh! Ow!
啊！噢！
Ta-da!
哒哒！
Piggyback for the king!
为国王背驮！
Let's see how fast
this old lady can go.
让我们看看有多快
这位老太太可以走了。
Hi-yah!
嗨呀！
- [yowling]
- [嚎叫]
- Yee-ha!
- 耶哈！
Today, Sea Chimps,
tomorrow, the world!
今天，海黑猩猩，
明天，世界！
I rule you, I rule you,
and I rule...you...
我统治你，我统治你，
我统治...你...
[groans]
[呻吟]
[screeching]
[尖叫声]
[groaning]
[呻吟]
Hey, what is this?
嘿，这是什么？
Where am I?
我在哪里？
Okay, ha-ha.
好吧，哈哈。
Very humorous.
非常幽默。
Having a bit of fun
玩得开心
with the king,
[chuckles] I get it.
与国王，
[笑]我明白了。
I think my armpits are dry now.
You can cut me down.
我觉得我的腋窝现在很干燥。
你可以砍倒我。
[laughing awkwardly]
[尴尬地笑]
I demand you obey your king!
我要求你服从你的国王！
Let's go!
Come on you little bozos!
我们走吧！
加油你们这些小笨蛋！
Get me down!
给我下来！
Guys?
My people? Loyal subjects?
伙计们？
我的人？忠诚的臣民？
[gulping]
Buddies?
[吞咽]
哥们？
- Oh! Hello! Remember me?
- 哦！你好！记住账号？
You took my crown
and became the new king?
你夺走了我的皇冠
并成为新国王？
I just wanted to say
thanks again.
我只是想说
再次感谢。
Oh, and, uh,
have a nice sacrifice!
哦，还有，呃，
有一个美好的牺牲！
- Sacrifice?
- 牺牲？
[all chanting "Tongue"]
[所有人都高呼“舌头”]
- Tongue?
That's a weird request.
- 舌头？
这是一个奇怪的要求。
But as king I'll be benevolent.
但作为国王我会仁慈的。
Gah!
What in Neptune's naval...?
嘎！
海王星的海军里有什么……？
[all chanting "Tongue"]
[所有人都高呼“舌头”]
Hey! Whoa!
嘿！哇！
Yuck! Time to un-shrink!
哎呀！是时候不收缩了！
Can't...reach...I take it back.
I don't want to be king!
无法...到达...我收回它。
我不想当国王！
- Uh-uh-uh.
No takee-backsees.
- 呃呃呃。
没有后顾之忧。
all: Aww.
- What do you mean, "aww"?
全体：哇。
- 你是什么意思，“哇”？
Don't aww!
别啊哇！
- Ow! That hurt.
- 噢！那很痛。
[laughing]
Now that snack's got a bite.
[笑]
现在那零食已经咬了一口了。
[all screaming]
[所有人尖叫]
- [wailing]
- [哀号]
- Oh, don't worry, sire!
- 哦，别担心，陛下！
I will cut you loose
from the sacrifice.
我会放开你
来自牺牲。
[chomping]
[咀嚼]
- Hey, stop!
Nice old Chimp king.
- 嘿，停下来！
漂亮的老黑猩猩国王。
Don't do that!
不要那样做！
Ahh!
啊！
[Sea Chimps screaming]
[海黑猩猩尖叫]
- [gulping]
- [吞咽]
- How did you get over there?
- 你是怎么到那里的？
[snapping]
Ahh!
[啪啪啪]
啊！
- Hey, you're welcome!
- 嘿，不客气！
- Hey, dumbbell.
- 嘿，哑铃。
Take this end of the belt
and wrap it around
拿起皮带的这一端
并将其包裹起来
all the other falling
numbskulls
所有其他的落下
麻木的头骨
and bring it back to me!
把它带回来给我！
It stretches.
Go!
它伸展。
去！
[all screaming]
[所有人尖叫]
You morons should cushion
my fall nicely.
你们这些白痴应该缓冲一下
我的秋天很好。
[all screaming]
[Patrick gulping]
[所有人尖叫]
[帕特里克吞咽]
- [humming]
[screaming]
- [嗡嗡声]
[尖叫]
Oh, Oh-oh! Patrick!
哦，哦，哦！帕特里克！
It was you trying to eat
my Sea Chimps the whole time.
是你想吃东西
我的海黑猩猩一直在。
- [scoffing]
- [嘲笑]
I can't believe you'd accuse me
of--of--such a delicious thing.
我不敢相信你会指控我
如此美味的东西。
[belches]
[打嗝]
[rumbling]
[隆隆声]
- I hear 'em in there.
- 我听到他们在那里。
- Hey, King, what's this
dialy-doodle-mojig
- 嘿，国王，这是什么？
Dialy 涂鸦 mojig
on your belt do?
- No, don't touch that!
你的腰带上有什么吗？
- 不，别碰那个！
- Whoa-oh-oh-oh!
- 哇哦哦！
I take it back.
They weren't that delicious.
我收回它。
它们没那么好吃。
- Whoa! Hey guys, come on out.
There's more room out here.
- 哇！嘿伙计们，出来吧。
这里还有更多空间。
[all screeching excitedly]
[大家兴奋地尖叫]
- Uhh.
- 呃。
- Partially digested antennae.
- 部分消化的触角。
- Welcome, Sea Chimps.
I'm SpongeBob, your owner.
- 欢迎，海黑猩猩。
我是海绵宝宝，你的主人。
- Forget it, man.
We're through with owners,
- 忘了它吧，伙计。
我们已经和业主谈完了，
and kings, and aquariums.
还有国王和水族馆。
Whoa! Now that looks like
a swell place to live.
哇！现在看起来像
一个舒适的居住地。
[all screeching]
[全都尖叫]
- Ah! Plankton!
Abandon bucket!
- 啊！浮游生物！
放弃桶！
- Well, that's a write off.
- 嗯，这是一笔注销。
[winding]
[绕线]
[Sea Chimps "Whoa!"]
[海黑猩猩“哇！”]
- Bye, Sea Chimps!
Have a good flight!
- 再见，海黑猩猩！
祝您飞行愉快！
That was so nice of you
to help relocate
你真是太好了
帮助搬迁
the Sea Chimps, Plankton.
You rule!
海黑猩猩，浮游生物。
你统治！
- Not today, SpongeBob.
Not today.
- 今天不行，海绵宝宝。
不是今天。
But...someday!
但是……总有一天！
[maniacal laughing]
[疯狂的大笑]
Oh!
- [gulping, belching]
哦！
- [吞咽，打嗝]
[ukulele music]
[尤克里里音乐]
♪ ♪